THEODORE AYOUB

Phone: (315)939-9597 | Email: theodore.ayoub@gmail.com | Oceanside, CA

LinkedIn: https://www.linkedin.com/in/theodore-ayoub-iii-07610922/ | GitHub: https://qithub.com/tenues0

Portfolio: https://tenues0.github.io/Portfolio/

SUMMARY

U.S. Military veteran, with active TS clearance, experienced in leading teams in technical environments and high-level operations. Selected to attend a computer science graduate program in Monterey, California while on active duty. Currently pursuing a certificate in Full Stack Development from the UC San Diego Extension with newly developed skills in HTML5, CSS3, JavaScript, JQuery, Bootstrap, Node.is, MySQL, MongoDB, Express, Handelbars.is, and ReactJS.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

JavaScript ES6+, CSS3, HTML5, Python, SQL, NoSQL, GitHub, MongoDB, MySQL, Express, React, Node, Handlebars, jQuery, Bootstrap

PROJECTS

Weather Dashboard

- This project was created using HTML, CSS, and JavaScript
- The project uses the OpenWeather One Call API 1.0 to pull information. A user can search for a city and the next weeks forecast will be displayed onto the screen.
- GitHub: https://github.com/tenues0/JS WEATHER DASHBOARD
- Website link: https://tenues0.github.io/JS Weather Dashboard

SQL Employee Tracker

- This project was created using SQL, JavaScript, node.js, express.js, sequelize, and inquirer.
- The project tracks employees using node.js and a SQL backend. A user can add departments, roles, and employees. The employee roles can also be updated.
- GitHub: https://github.com/tenues0/SQL Employee Tracker

EXPERIENCE

Network Engineer MCTSSA

2020-Present Oceanside, CA

Serving out utilization tour after completing graduate program in computer science Kev Accomplishments:

- Served in the Cyber test department, conducted cyber testing on VSAT-Terminal.
- Completed 35 hour project management course and successfully passed PMP exam.
- Coordinated resources to host several test events for outside contractors at MCTSSA.
- Lead planner for family events: Halloween party, beach bash, as well as, other monthly functions.

Graduate Computer Science Student Naval Postgraduate School

2018-2020 Monterey, CA

Selected to attend graduate program under Commandant's Career Level Education Board Key Accomplishments:

- Took over 35 computer science courses to go from zero to master's graduate.
- Completed thesis on computer vision and machine learning.

Communications Officer US Marine Corps

2013-2018

Camp Pendleton, CA

Served in a variety of job roles as an entry level officer

Key Accomplishments:

- Promoted to Captain during first tour as an officer; awarded Navy Commendation medal for outstanding performance in duties during first tour as an officer.
- Completed master's degree in operations management through the University of Arkansas on a part time basis during first tour.

- Served as the lead planner for the Battalion Force Modernization Restructure by conducting a comprehensive Table of Organization and Equipment review. All \$113,982,598.60 worth of equipment at 9th COMM BN was analyzed and realigned to the new BN mission; (86) TAMCNs items were directly impacted.
- As a lieutenant, served as the Battalion Operations Officer (a majors billet) during several MEF scale exercises.
- Developed professional education plan for platoon consisting of Case studies and mentorship classes to foster NCO development; a trend that was used in adjacent companies throughout the battalion.
- Served as a transmissions platoon commander in charge of 43 Marines and responsible for (37) high value communications assets worth \$19.6 Million dollars.

EDUCATION

Full Stack Web Development Certificate (March 2022 - September 2022)

UC San Diego Extension

San Diego, CA

A 24-week intensive program focused on gaining technical programming skills.

Project Management Professional Certification (Issued Dec 2020)

Credential ID 2932994

Masters of Science in Computer Science (January 2018 - June 2020)

Naval Postgraduate School

Monterey, California

Masters of Science in Operations Management (June 2015 - June 2020)

University of Arkansas

Fayetteville (online), Arkansas

Bachelors of Science in Mechanical Engineering (January 2007 – May 2012)

SUNY Polytechnic Institute

Utica, New York